My Contact

malik059@umn.edu



+92 303 2091785



Karachi, Pakistan

Hard Skill

- · Administrative Skills
- Operating database systems
- · Financial management and budgeting
- Project Management
- · Data Analysis
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS and Javascript)

Soft Skill

- · Customer Service
- Decision making
- Leadership and Team Management
- Multi-tasking
- Adaptability
- Communication and Interpersonal skills

Education Background

University of Minnesota, Morris Bachelors in Economics, Minor: Statistics Completed in 2017

About Me

An experienced administrative professional with years of extensive experience in project coordination, handling confidential information, delivering top-notch customer service, and formulating strategies to accomplish organizational objectives. Adept at implementing process improvements in various administrative functions, including policy and procedure planning.

Professional Experience

Cafe Qayam | Sole Proprietor/Executive Manager

March 2022 - Present

- Leading and managing all restaurant employees in a fast-paced working environment
- Implementing innovative marketing strategies to increase business sales
- · Managing all financial and operational aspects of the business
- · Hiring and training a diverse team of staff members

Kaiser Restaurant | Senior Manager

September 2018 - February 2022

- Administered operations on a daily basis and ensured protocol was followed by staff
- Reviewed financial transactions and allocated restaurant budget more efficiently
- Managed food inventory, ensuring stock was sufficient at all times
- Monitored food preparation to ensure 100% customer satisfaction

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - Office of the Registrar | Executive Operations and Administrative **Specialist**

- Served as the team lead for the Imaging unit in regards to managing day-to-day
- activities of the student workers
- Processed enrollment requests for non-degree graduate and undergraduate students.
- Participated in project prioritization, strategic planning, and business process improvements for the Imaging unit and the Office of the Registrar.

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi

- Supervised daily operations of the imaging unit, ensuring it's efficient and effective functioning
- Managed important/confidential documents in database systems.
- Ensured that best practices and academic records integrity are upheld and documented
- Tracked and analysed statistics to determine needs and enhancements in order to ensure service levels are maintained
- Supported the Office of the Registrar as an expert in Duplicate ID resolution
- Planned and managed departmental budget

University of Minnesota, Morris - One Stop Student Services | Customer Relations Representative

- Worked with applications such as Salesforce and People soft to manage student information
- Handled all student inquiries via phone, email and in person
- Record Keeping of One Stop counsellors schedule and availability

My Contact

malik059@umn.edu



+92 303 2091785



Karachi, Pakistan

Hard Skill

- · Administrative Skills
- Operating database systems
- · Financial management and budgeting
- Project Management
- · Data Analysis
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS and Javascript)

Soft Skill

- · Customer Service
- Decision making
- Leadership and Team Management
- Multi-tasking
- Adaptability
- Communication and Interpersonal skills

Education Background

University of Minnesota, Morris Bachelors in Economics, Minor: Statistics Completed in 2017

About Me

An experienced administrative professional with years of extensive experience in project coordination, handling confidential information, delivering top-notch customer service, and formulating strategies to accomplish organizational objectives. Adept at implementing process improvements in various administrative functions, including policy and procedure planning.

Professional Experience

Cafe Qayam | Sole Proprietor/Executive Manager

March 2022 - Present

- Leading and managing all restaurant employees in a fast-paced working environment
- Implementing innovative marketing strategies to increase business sales
- · Managing all financial and operational aspects of the business
- · Hiring and training a diverse team of staff members

Kaiser Restaurant | Senior Manager

September 2018 - February 2022

- Administered operations on a daily basis and ensured protocol was followed by staff
- Reviewed financial transactions and allocated restaurant budget more efficiently
- Managed food inventory, ensuring stock was sufficient at all times
- Monitored food preparation to ensure 100% customer satisfaction

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - Office of the Registrar | Executive Operations and Administrative **Specialist**

- Served as the team lead for the Imaging unit in regards to managing day-to-day
- activities of the student workers
- Processed enrollment requests for non-degree graduate and undergraduate students.
- Participated in project prioritization, strategic planning, and business process improvements for the Imaging unit and the Office of the Registrar.

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi

- Supervised daily operations of the imaging unit, ensuring it's efficient and effective functioning
- Managed important/confidential documents in database systems.
- Ensured that best practices and academic records integrity are upheld and documented
- Tracked and analysed statistics to determine needs and enhancements in order to ensure service levels are maintained
- Supported the Office of the Registrar as an expert in Duplicate ID resolution
- Planned and managed departmental budget

University of Minnesota, Morris - One Stop Student Services | Customer Relations Representative

- Worked with applications such as Salesforce and People soft to manage student information
- Handled all student inquiries via phone, email and in person
- Record Keeping of One Stop counsellors schedule and availability

My Contact

malik059@umn.edu



+92 303 2091785



Karachi, Pakistan

Hard Skill

- · Administrative Skills
- Operating database systems
- · Financial management and budgeting
- Project Management
- · Data Analysis
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS and Javascript)

Soft Skill

- · Customer Service
- Decision making
- Leadership and Team Management
- Multi-tasking
- Adaptability
- Communication and Interpersonal skills

Education Background

University of Minnesota, Morris Bachelors in Economics, Minor: Statistics Completed in 2017

About Me

An experienced administrative professional with years of extensive experience in project coordination, handling confidential information, delivering top-notch customer service, and formulating strategies to accomplish organizational objectives. Adept at implementing process improvements in various administrative functions, including policy and procedure planning.

Professional Experience

Cafe Qayam | Sole Proprietor/Executive Manager

March 2022 - Present

- Leading and managing all restaurant employees in a fast-paced working environment
- Implementing innovative marketing strategies to increase business sales
- · Managing all financial and operational aspects of the business
- · Hiring and training a diverse team of staff members

Kaiser Restaurant | Senior Manager

September 2018 - February 2022

- Administered operations on a daily basis and ensured protocol was followed by staff
- Reviewed financial transactions and allocated restaurant budget more efficiently
- Managed food inventory, ensuring stock was sufficient at all times
- Monitored food preparation to ensure 100% customer satisfaction

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - Office of the Registrar | Executive Operations and Administrative **Specialist**

- Served as the team lead for the Imaging unit in regards to managing day-to-day
- activities of the student workers
- Processed enrollment requests for non-degree graduate and undergraduate students.
- Participated in project prioritization, strategic planning, and business process improvements for the Imaging unit and the Office of the Registrar.

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi

- Supervised daily operations of the imaging unit, ensuring it's efficient and effective functioning
- Managed important/confidential documents in database systems.
- Ensured that best practices and academic records integrity are upheld and documented
- Tracked and analysed statistics to determine needs and enhancements in order to ensure service levels are maintained
- Supported the Office of the Registrar as an expert in Duplicate ID resolution
- Planned and managed departmental budget

University of Minnesota, Morris - One Stop Student Services | Customer Relations Representative

- Worked with applications such as Salesforce and People soft to manage student information
- Handled all student inquiries via phone, email and in person
- Record Keeping of One Stop counsellors schedule and availability

DANISH MALIK

+92 309 1116366 | malikdanishk@gmail.com | linkedin.com/danish-malik-k | github.com/malikdanishkhan

Creative and committed problem-solver with a solid background in application development, object-oriented programming principles and intermediate experience with data management/analysis.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Java • C++ • GO • Elixir

Front-end technologies:

AngularJS • HTML5 • CSS3 • Bootstrap

Back-end technologies:

Node.js • jQuery • Ajax • Axios

Databases:

MySQL • SQL Server • MongoDB

Cloud Technologies:

Microsoft Azure • AWS • GCP

Tools:

Sublime • IntelliJ • Eclipse PowerApps • Power BI

Zendesk • Jira

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

B.A in Computer Science Morris, MN – December 2018

COURSEWORK

Data Structures (Java & C++) Algorithms & Computability Software Design & Development Human-Computer Interaction

Programming for Parallel Architecture Cryptography
Discrete Mathematics Calculus I III III Differential
Equations

PROJECTS

YelpCamp – *Full Stack Developer* October 2018 – December 2018

> Built RESTful web APIs using Express.js and mongoDB to follow a subset of Yelp functionalities for camping sites, incorporating google maps API from Google Cloud Platform to implement the feature of campsite locations.

Sage Vocabulary Game – *Full Stack Developer* August 2017 – December 2017

 Collaborated with cross-functional team members using Agile Development Cycle to build a web application for elementary students to enhance their vocabulary skills.

EXPERIENCE

Pestle Tech – *Software Developer* Karachi, PK // April 2021 – March 2022

- Designed and developed the company's primary website for digital services (<u>www.mabbly.co.uk</u>) using HTML5, CSS3 and IS.
- Performed maintenance on the company's secondary website (<u>www.ghostwritingmuser.com</u>) that offers ghostwriting services in the US.
- Deployed websites and set up hosting for clients on WordPress, Hostinger and Bluehost.

Freelancer – Full Stack Developer Karachi, PK // July 2020 – March 2021

- Developed web applications for several different businesses including restaurants, architecture and accountant firms.
- Completed projects and set up hosting for clients from US,
 Nigeria and Pakistan after iterated reviews.

Doctors Without Borders (Médecins Sans Frontières) — *Systems Applications Intern*

New York, NY // May 2019 - September 2019

- Optimized processes by developing a secure data repository using PowerApps and SQL server for HROs to store information regarding field workers located globally.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to generate reports and data visualization charts using Power BI to outline the departments daily performance in meetings.
- Supported IT Project Managers in third-party meetings for several projects within a variety of workstreams.
- Resolved technical issues experienced by end users by troubleshooting and responding to IT support tickets submitted through Help Desk.

All Rise Ventures — *Software Developer Intern* New York, NY // July 2018 — August 2018

- Improved the UI design of the firm's website using WIX to maximize usability and user experience.
- Devised a cost-effective social media marketing strategy to reduce advertisement costs, in addition to designing digital media content.
- Set-up organizational tools including Dropbox to store data and Slack for communication.
- Managed the company's blog site by writing and finding articles as well as case studies to support the company's motive of impact investment.

My Contact

malik059@umn.edu



+92 303 2091785



Karachi, Pakistan

Hard Skill

- · Administrative Skills
- Operating database systems
- · Financial management and budgeting
- Project Management
- · Data Analysis
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS and Javascript)

Soft Skill

- · Customer Service
- Decision making
- Leadership and Team Management
- Multi-tasking
- Adaptability
- Communication and Interpersonal skills

Education Background

University of Minnesota, Morris Bachelors in Economics, Minor: Statistics Completed in 2017

About Me

An experienced administrative professional with years of extensive experience in project coordination, handling confidential information, delivering top-notch customer service, and formulating strategies to accomplish organizational objectives. Adept at implementing process improvements in various administrative functions, including policy and procedure planning.

Professional Experience

Cafe Qayam | Sole Proprietor/Executive Manager

March 2022 - Present

- Leading and managing all restaurant employees in a fast-paced working environment
- Implementing innovative marketing strategies to increase business sales
- · Managing all financial and operational aspects of the business
- · Hiring and training a diverse team of staff members

Kaiser Restaurant | Senior Manager

September 2018 - February 2022

- Administered operations on a daily basis and ensured protocol was followed by staff
- Reviewed financial transactions and allocated restaurant budget more efficiently
- Managed food inventory, ensuring stock was sufficient at all times
- Monitored food preparation to ensure 100% customer satisfaction

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - Office of the Registrar | Executive Operations and Administrative **Specialist**

- Served as the team lead for the Imaging unit in regards to managing day-to-day
- activities of the student workers
- Processed enrollment requests for non-degree graduate and undergraduate students.
- Participated in project prioritization, strategic planning, and business process improvements for the Imaging unit and the Office of the Registrar.

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi

- Supervised daily operations of the imaging unit, ensuring it's efficient and effective functioning
- Managed important/confidential documents in database systems.
- Ensured that best practices and academic records integrity are upheld and documented
- Tracked and analysed statistics to determine needs and enhancements in order to ensure service levels are maintained
- Supported the Office of the Registrar as an expert in Duplicate ID resolution
- Planned and managed departmental budget

University of Minnesota, Morris - One Stop Student Services | Customer Relations Representative

- Worked with applications such as Salesforce and People soft to manage student information
- Handled all student inquiries via phone, email and in person
- Record Keeping of One Stop counsellors schedule and availability

My Contact

malik059@umn.edu



+92 303 2091785



Karachi, Pakistan

Hard Skill

- · Administrative Skills
- Operating database systems
- · Financial management and budgeting
- Project Management
- · Data Analysis
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS and Javascript)

Soft Skill

- · Customer Service
- Decision making
- Leadership and Team Management
- Multi-tasking
- Adaptability
- Communication and Interpersonal skills

Education Background

University of Minnesota, Morris Bachelors in Economics, Minor: Statistics Completed in 2017

About Me

An experienced administrative professional with years of extensive experience in project coordination, handling confidential information, delivering top-notch customer service, and formulating strategies to accomplish organizational objectives. Adept at implementing process improvements in various administrative functions, including policy and procedure planning.

Professional Experience

Cafe Qayam | Sole Proprietor/Executive Manager

March 2022 - Present

- Leading and managing all restaurant employees in a fast-paced working environment
- Implementing innovative marketing strategies to increase business sales
- · Managing all financial and operational aspects of the business
- · Hiring and training a diverse team of staff members

Kaiser Restaurant | Senior Manager

September 2018 - February 2022

- Administered operations on a daily basis and ensured protocol was followed by staff
- Reviewed financial transactions and allocated restaurant budget more efficiently
- Managed food inventory, ensuring stock was sufficient at all times
- Monitored food preparation to ensure 100% customer satisfaction

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - Office of the Registrar | Executive Operations and Administrative **Specialist**

- Served as the team lead for the Imaging unit in regards to managing day-to-day
- activities of the student workers
- Processed enrollment requests for non-degree graduate and undergraduate students.
- Participated in project prioritization, strategic planning, and business process improvements for the Imaging unit and the Office of the Registrar.

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi

- Supervised daily operations of the imaging unit, ensuring it's efficient and effective functioning
- Managed important/confidential documents in database systems.
- Ensured that best practices and academic records integrity are upheld and documented
- Tracked and analysed statistics to determine needs and enhancements in order to ensure service levels are maintained
- Supported the Office of the Registrar as an expert in Duplicate ID resolution
- Planned and managed departmental budget

University of Minnesota, Morris - One Stop Student Services | Customer Relations Representative

- Worked with applications such as Salesforce and People soft to manage student information
- Handled all student inquiries via phone, email and in person
- Record Keeping of One Stop counsellors schedule and availability